AFP stands for Apple File Service. It provides a means of remotely browsing and modifying the contents of your AppleTV from the Finder in a Macintosh.

After enabling this service, you will be able to connect to your AppleTV directly using the Macintosh Finder using one of the following two procedures:

The Easy Method
In the Finder, press Command-Shift-K, or select the Network item in the sidebar of an existing Finder window. If you see a My Network folder here, click it. Inside this folder you should see an alias with the name you gave your AppleTV. Double-click this to initiate the connection.

The More Involved Method
On your AppleTV, go into Settings and note down the IP address. Now go to your Macintosh, switch to the Finder and press Command-K, or choose the 'Connect To Server…' option from the 'Go' menu. In the entry field of the panel that opens, type the IP address of your AppleTV. You can use the '+' button to store this address for later use. Click 'Connect' to initiate the connection.

Logging In
Assuming the previous steps worked, you will now be presented with a dialog asking for a username and password. By default, you will need to use 'frontrow' for both of these. Although it is possible to change the password, it is unknown at present what effect this will have on the AppleTV system -- doing so may prevent it from starting up.

After entering the name and password, you will be presented with a list of available volumes. There will be 'frontrow', which is the home folder used in conjunction with the ATVFiles media browser plugin -- mount this and add items to the Movies folder to have them show up there. There is also the 'OSBoot' volume containing the AppleTV operating system (this is read-only by default) and 'Media' which contains the media synchronized to your AppleTV from within iTunes. This last partition is modifiable, and so contains files such as system logs and modified preferences within the 'Scratch' folder at its root.