The SSH service enables you to remotely log into your AppleTV using the Secure Shell terminal software included on all Apple Macs.

Once this is enabled, you will need to find the IP address of your AppleTV from the Settings menu, and issue a command similar to the following within the Terminal application on your OS X machine:

ssh frontrow@10.0.1.2

Replace the '10.0.1.2' with the IP address of your AppleTV.

The first time you connect, you will be prompted that the server is not already known to the client, and will be asked whether it is to be trusted. You should type 'yes' and press enter to continue.

When prompted for a password, enter 'frontrow' and press enter. The password will not show up on screen, this is normal.

If this means nothing to you, then you probably don't need to enable it.